neuvoo.ca 2019-11-29

# neuvoo. Your job search starts here.

By using NEUVOO, you agree to the following terms: 

##  1\. Content 

All the jobs contained in NEUVOO's search results, or linked from those results, have been provided by external websites over whom NEUVOO exercises no control. NEUVOO automatically indexes all the jobs from external sources and assumes no responsibility for the content of any job listing. 

##  2\. Service 

NEUVOO provides its search platform for personal (non-commercial) job seekers. If you wish to make commercial use of NEUVOO’s platform, you must enter into an agreement with NEUVOO. 

##  3\. Liability 

NEUVOO is not liable for any kind of physical, financial or psychological damage caused by the use of our search service. If you find content on NEUVOO’s website that could be potentially harmful, please contact us. Our team will investigate and take action to fix the problem swiftly. 

##  4\. Guarantee 

NEUVOO's team is working hard to maintain a high quality of indexed jobs. Because we index a lot of content, we cannot guarantee the validity and genuineness of all the jobs we index. If you find any jobs that look "spammy", "fishy" or "expired", please contact us. Our team will investigate and take action to fix the problem swiftly. 

##  5\. Indexing of NEUVOO 

We do not allow the automatic indexing/crawling of NEUVOO's search results outside of the rules provided by our robots.txt file. (See neuvoo.com/robots.txt) 

##  6\. Changes in Terms of Service 

NEUVOO’s terms of use may change in the future, at NEUVOO’s discretion. Any changes will be announced on this page. 

Here’s what you need to know about our security measures:

##  1\. Protection 

We continuously test our system for potential breaches. We have dedicated resources monitoring our servers for any potential intrusions or hack attempts. We use SSL when necessary and have strict access control policies within our organization. We use Firewall on sensitive servers and run anti-virus programs regularly. No system is 100% secure, so we dedicate resources to ensure that we minimize the risk of leaks, breaches, or hacks. 

##  2\. Links 

As a search engine, most clicks will forward users to the source website. We do our best to remove sources containing malware, excessive advertising, phishing strategies, or any other method potentially harming our users or degrading their job search experience. If you run into a link that contains any of these qualities, please contact us. We will investigate and take action swiftly. 

##  3\. Cookies 

NEUVOO uses cookies. “Cookies” are text-based files that a server (NEUVOO) and a browser (YOU) share to keep track of certain events or preferences. NEUVOO uses cookies for the following: 

**Simplify your subscription to email alerts.** The email address is stored for up to 1 month, so you don't have to re-enter it every time you subscribe to a new alert. 

**Analytics.** Allows us to keep statistics on visitors sources. For example, other websites visitors come from. This data is automatically purged after 1 hour. 

Cookies are temporary and anonymous, and can be deleted from your browser at any point. 

Thank you for using NEUVOO as your job search engine! 

The following Privacy Policy describes how NEUVOO collects, handles, and processes your data when you use or interact with our websites and services. For a simplified version of this policy, please click  here . 

When this policy mentions “NEUVOO,” “we,” “us,” or “our,” it refers to NEUVOO INC., the Canadian-based company in charge of collecting, handling, and processing your information. Neuvoo, Inc. is a job aggregator that indexes all jobs available online so you can find every job listed online on one single website.

##  1\. **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

In order for us to better serve our visitors and users (“you”), there are two categories of information we collect: 

##  1.1 **Long-term Data**

“Long-term Data” refers to any data we collect to offer you a better job seeking and application experience. “Long-term Data” includes the following: 

**_Account Creation._** When you apply for a job through NEUVOO’s platform, we save your first name, last name, email address, phone number, and last uploaded resume (i.e. most recently uploaded attachment) and associate it with an Account, so you can easily apply for subsequent jobs without having to re-enter your application information every time. 

Should you choose not to upload your resume, you might be asked to give more information on your work experience, education, certifications/licenses and skills, among others. In most cases, providing this information is not required for you to apply, which is why you are free to choose whether to give it or not. If you do, this information will also be associated with your Account, so you can easily apply for subsequent jobs without having to re-enter your application information every time. If you choose not to share this information, you can, in most cases, proceed to applying for the job. However, there are some cases where work experience, education, certifications/licenses and skills, among others, may be required by the employer, in order for them to make hiring decisions. In those specific cases, choosing not to give this information will prevent you from applying for the job. 

We also collect your job search history (jobs viewed, jobs added to favourites, jobs applied for, keywords and location typed in the search bar) to give you better and more personalized results so that you are able to find jobs you are interested in faster and easier. 

In order to keep you logged into your account as you navigate our website, we also collect and store cookies that are purged the second you log out. 

**_Email Alerts._** When you subscribe to NEUVOO’s Email Alerts service (also commonly referred to as “Job Alerts”), we collect your email address, as well as the keyword(s) and location typed in the search bar or displayed on the job posting from which you subscribed to email alerts. That way, we can email you personalized and relevant job listings related to your job search. 

Please note that you may manage your alerts or unsubscribe at any given time by clicking on the “Unsubscribe from Job Alert” link at the bottom of any email alert. You can then click on the “Delete” button next to the alert you wish to remove. 

**_Traffic Quality._** We collect IP addresses and information on the device, operating system, and browser used to access our jobs. This information is stored separately from all other information and is anonymized in a way that it cannot be tied to any other information that can be used to identify you as an individual. This helps us guarantee that our traffic is genuine and acts as proof that real people click on our jobs—not robots. 

**_Salary._** When applying for jobs, you may be asked about your current and desired salary. This information will never get automatically transmitted to employers, unless it is part of the “Short-Term Data” required by employers. Providing this information is not mandatory, but if you choose to do so, our Hiring Specialists will be able to access this data and can use it to help you negotiate your salary with employers interested in your profile. However, you should know that Hiring Specialists usually get in touch with you prior to discussing your profile with the employer. 

The main purpose of asking for Salary information is to better tailor the content we are showing and sending you. You can read more about Content Customization in section 2 (“HOW WE USE INFORMATION”). 

##  1.2. **Short-term Data**

"Short-Term Data" refers to any information that is requested by an employer in order for a job seeker to successfully apply for the employer's job, aside from the information already mentioned above in the "Long-Term Data" section. 

Some of the most common examples of “Short-term Data” are level of proficiency with certain programs; level of fluency with certain spoken or written languages; other skill assessments; or external links, such as portfolio links. 

When you apply for jobs and submit your application to employers directly through NEUVOO, we act as an intermediary between you and the employer. We collect this data temporarily in order to automatically transmit it to the employer on your behalf. 

##  1.2.1 **Important Notice**

Once an application is transmitted to an employer, NEUVOO cannot reverse the process or retrieve any data that was already transmitted to the employer’s end. 

When you apply to a job using NEUVOO, you understand and agree that your application information is sent to the employer and that once your application is transmitted, the process cannot be undone since a copy of your information will already have reached the employer’s end. 

##  2\. **HOW WE USE INFORMATION**

**_Content Customization._** We use the information we collect to provide a personalized, simplified job seeking and application experience, whether it is showing you job listings tailored to your needs, sending you customized email alerts, or offering you a one-stop platform where you can apply to all the jobs you are interested in with your application data being automatically and transparently transmitted to the employers. 

**_More Job Opportunities._** We use your application information to provide you with job opportunities you may have missed or that have not been shared with the rest of our users. Our Hiring Specialists are always looking for outstanding candidates, so, if your profile matches an employer’s requirement, we will reach out to let you know. Please, know that prior to contacting you, our Hiring Specialists may review your application information – including your resume if you chose to attach one – in order for them to determine whether you would be a good fit for the role. 

**_Services Improvement._** We use an anonymized version of your IP address to see how different users interact with our services so that we can better improve them. 

##  2.1 **How long we keep your information**

“Long-term Data” (see 1.1) is stored in our system for as long as we need it to successfully provide our services—or until you wish to purge it (see 5.3). For example, in the case of Email Alerts, we need to store your email address so that we are able to send you the alerts you have subscribed to. You can access, manage, and purge “Long-term Data” by logging into your NEUVOO account (see 6.1). 

“Short-term Data” (see 1.2) is stored in our system as long as employers need access to it.. We keep it in case the transmission of your information to the employer has failed and we need to retransmit it to them. You may also purge your “Short-term Data” at any time by logging into your NEUVOO account (see 6.1). 

Please, know that as long as you have a NEUVOO account, we assume you keep applying for jobs or will do so in the foreseeable future. Therefore, we keep your information available to keep you from re-entering it manually the next time you choose to apply. 

##  2.2 **How your information is stored**

Information we collect is transferred to, processed, and stored in Canada. The protection of your privacy and personal information is important to us. NEUVOO is committed to handling and processing your data in the most secure way and places great importance on the way your information is being handled and processed. We have a team assigned on all data security matters and are continuously working on new features to keep your information secure. 

We only disclose the information we collect from you as described below:

We may share your anonymized IP address to our partners or clients, but we never pair it with “Long-term Data” or “Short-term Data”. The reason why we share this information with our partners is for traffic quality assurance. This information acts as proof that real people click on their content—not robots.

When applying for a job, we ask you for your consent before we can share your application information with the employer who posted the job you are applying for. If you proceed to apply to the job, you understand that your application information will be submitted to the employer and that, as detailed in 1.2.1, this process cannot be reversed.

We will never sell any of your information to advertisers or third parties.

## 4\. **CONSENT**

We only collect and process your personal data where you have given us explicit consent to do so.

## 4.1 **Withdrawing consent**

You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. The withdrawal of your consent does not affect any processing that has already taken place before the withdrawal. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent may prevent you from further using some of our services. 

##  5\. **YOUR RIGHTS**

##  5.1 **Right of access**

You have the right to know whether your personal data is being processed and, where that is the case, access to the personal data. We can provide a copy of the personal data undergoing processing upon your request (see 5.5), unless it affects the rights and freedoms of others. 

If you have concerns about the purposes of your data processing, the categories of personal data concerned, the parties to whom it is disclosed, or the period of time during which we store your data, please contact us and we will gladly clarify any doubts you may have on the matter. 

##  5.2 **Right to rectification**

You can modify most personal information we collect from you by logging into your account (see 6.1). If you were in a situation where you would not be able to edit the information you would wish to correct, please contact us with detailed information on the data you wish to rectify so we can address your issue in a timely manner. 

##  5.3 **Right to erasure**

You have the right to obtain the erasure of your personal data without undue delay and may do so by logging into your account (see 6.1). 

NEUVOO has the obligation to erase said data when it is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed. We will also erase your personal data if you withdraw consent on the processing of your data (see 4.1) or object to its processing (see 5.6). 

In the unlikely event that you are unable to purge your information yourself (i.e. following the steps detailed in 6.1), please contact us with detailed information on the data you wish to erase so we can address your issue in a timely manner. 

## 5.4 **Right to restriction of processing**

You have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data for a period enabling us to verify the accuracy of your data. You may also choose to restrict the processing of your data rather than completely erasing it from our system, in which case you will need to contact us.

## 5.5 **Right to data portability**

You have the right to receive a copy of the personal data you have provided us, in the event where this data can be traced back to you, as an individual. You may request a copy of your personal data by contacting us. You also have the right to transmit said data to another party. 

## 5.6 **Right to object**

You have the right to object to the processing of your personal information and may do so at any time by contacting us.

##  6\. **MANAGING YOUR INFORMATION**

You have control over the information you choose to give us and may access, edit, or purge your information at any time. 

**6.1** **Accessing, editing, and erasing your information**

**_Account Information._** If you wish to access or edit your account information, you may do so by logging into your account. If you rather delete all information associated with your account (whether “Long-term Data” or “Short-term Data”), you may do so by logging into your account, clicking on the “Settings” section, and then on “Purge my account information”. All “Long-term Data” and “Short-term Data” associated with your account will be removed from our system permanently, including data associated with any email alerts you may be subscribed to. 

**_Email Alerts._** If you wish to access or edit your alerts, you may do so by clicking on the “Manage job alert settings” in the “Improve alert” section of any email alert. You will then be able to edit or remove individual alerts by clicking on the “Improve alert” button which allows you to change keywords and location or to improve relevancy. 

If you would rather unsubscribe, you may do so by clicking on the “Unsubscribe from Job Alert” link located at the bottom of any email alert. You can then click on the “Delete” button next to the alert you wish to remove. 

NEUVOO offers informational and educational content for Human Resources and Talent Acquisition professionals in the form of eBooks and PDF documents that can be downloaded from several landing pages powered by MailChimp. **These documents are addressed to professionals working in the recruitment and talent acquisition fields and should not be confused with other services and products that target job seekers and their data.**

We promote the eBook landing pages on our [Twitter](https://twitter.com/neuvoo) and [LinkedIn](https://www.linkedin.com/company/neuvoo-ca/) pages and also distribute a copy on a monthly basis to users who subscribed to receive new eBooks via email. Please note that you can cancel your subscription at any time by clicking on the “unsubscribe from this list” link at the bottom of our communications. 

## Information We Collect

When downloading an eBook, users are asked to fill a form with the following personal data:

  * Email Address
  * First Name
  * Last Name
  * Company Name
  * Country
  * Phone Number

There is also a field titled “Number of Employees”, which refers to the number of people working at the aforementioned company. Although this is not considered personal data, it is treated the same way.

## How We Use Your Information

We use the information you choose to provide us in one or more of the three ways you gave us consent to process. All our forms—the ones on our landing pages and the one on our blog—have a “Marketing Permissions” section where you can clearly indicate the reasons why you would like NEUVOO to contact you. Those are:

  * **Latest eBooks**

o We will use your information to send you our latest human resources and talent acquisition-related PDF documents.

  * **Latest Blog Articles**

o We will use your information to send you our newsletter, where we compile all the latest articles that were published on our blog.

  * **Exclusive Offers**

o We will use your information for more personalized communications to let you know of the many ways NEUVOO can help you improve your recruitment and talent acquisition strategies.

We also use Cookies on our landing pages. Please refer to section 3 of the Security section for more info on how we handle cookies for analytics purposes. 

## How We Store and Share Information

Our landing pages and mailing lists are powered by MailChimp, making MailChimp the Data Controller in this case. Therefore, we recommend you to have a look at MailChimp’s [Terms of Use](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/) and [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). 

Our policies are in place to help ensure a positive experience for all parties involved in our Publisher and API programs. All publishers are required to adhere to the following terms. If you, as a publisher, fail to comply with any of these terms without permission from NEUVOO, we reserve the right to suspend and close your account and cancel any scheduled payments immediately without further notice or official notification. Once your account is disabled, you may not be eligible for further participation in our publisher program.

Because our policies are subject to change at any time, please check the current page for update. It is your responsibility to keep up to date with, and adhere to, the policies listed here. Exceptions to these policies are permitted only with authorization from NEUVOO.

## What does a publisher do?

Publishers are third-party entities from whom NEUVOO buys traffic, as part of our traffic acquisition strategy. They publish our content on their website and send their visitors to our pages in exchange for a click-based rate which may vary depending on numerous factors, including the publisher’s country or exposure.

Our relationship with publishers is primary a partnership, meaning all parties involved shall benefit from it. Publishers must guarantee that they will bring quality traffic to our website, meaning all users browsing their websites must show genuine interest when clicking on our links and, hence, must agree to being redirected on our website and browse our content. Any publisher that does not follow this guideline may be exposed to severe consequences, such as account cancellation or disabling.

##  Invalid and misleading traffic: what is it and how do we prevent it? 

NEUVOO treats policy violations and invalid traffic very seriously in order to protect job seekers, publishers, and advertisers. We pay close attention to traffic behavior by analyzing all clicks to determine whether they fit a pattern of use that might artificially drive up an advertiser’s costs or a publisher’s earnings. 

More specifically, we sample part of the traffic to measure what we call “Intent of Apply” (IOA) which corresponds to the percentage of people who show genuine interest in applying on a given job. This is the most accurate indicator of users’ IOA as it requires them to fill out a quick form, showing they are interested in applying for the job they are reading about. The industry average is 10%, meaning for every 100 visitors, 10 are usually willing to fill the form in order to access the employer’s website. If a publisher’s IOA rate goes under a certain percentage, it triggers a quality assurance (QA) process, where we look for any invalid or misleading traffic sources, such as: 

  * Adult content websites; 
  * Malicious websites; 
  * Malware websites; 
  * Pop-under traffic; 
  * Iframed traffic; and 
  * Bulk unrelated traffic. 

If the majority of your traffic comes from any of the aforementioned channels we will consider it as invalid, as it does not bring quality traffic to our website and interferes with our site navigation. Please be advised that we will consider this as a violation of our agreement and will proceed to suspend or close your account without further notice. We will also cancel any scheduled payment and reimburse all other parties impacted by your traffic, if any.
